Okay.
Okay, I know, I know.
I'm sorry.
I know it's a little tender.
Hmm.
Okay, let's try your voice now.
"My name is Katniss Everdeen.
I'm from District 12."
- My...
- Okay, take your time.
Still got a lot of swelling
in your vocal chords.
My...
...name is...
...Katniss Everdeen.
I want...
I want to talk to him.
He needs time.
But, um, we're trying
somethin' new today.
He's been calmer
with the doctors,
but they're strangers to him.
So we're gonna
test his response
on someone
he remembers from home.
Someone he trusts.
Send her in.
Hey.
Prim.
How you feelin'?
- She's too close.
- Mmm, it's okay.
- How'd you get here?
- We live in District 13 now.
It's a real place.
Stories are true.
You were rescued.
My family hasn't come
to see me.
There was an attack on 12.
Yes.
My family?
The bakery didn't survive.
It's Katniss.
- It's because of Katniss.
- Wasn't because of her.
- She tell you to say that?
- She didn't tell me anything.
She's a liar, Prim.
It's a trick.
Peeta, what you're saying
isn't real.
She sent you here
to talk to me.
- She knows you're here now.
- It's okay.
She knows...
You can't trust her!
She's a monster!
She's a mutt that The Capitol
created to destroy us!
- Get her outta there.
- Do you understand me?
You have to kill her, Prim!
You have to kill her!
- Katniss?
- She's a mutt!
This is just
a conditioned response.
- Kill her!
- It's not him.
She's a monster! She's a mutt!
- No, it's not him.
- She's a mutt!
There's not enough
manpower coming in from 4.
I don't think that's a problem.
Please, come in.
With any kind
of manpower, if we...
Will you excuse us
for just a moment?
Of course.
Have a seat.
I'm glad you're feeling better.
Snow has to pay
for what he's done.
I wanna help the rebels
in any way I can.
It's hard to see
Peeta this way.
That's not Peeta.
Send me to The Capitol.
I'll do anything.
I can't...
I can't send you there.
We can't get into The Capitol
until we control District 2.
Then send me to 2.
You want me to
fire up our troops?
Call out to the loyalists?
You've seen what I can do.
Yes, I have.
I saw Peeta... before we left.
And what did you think?
Something selfish.
That you don't have to be
jealous of him anymore.
No.
I don't stand a chance
if he doesn't get better.
You'll never let him go.
What's goin' on
in your head?
I don't know.
That's like kissing someone
who's drunk.
Doesn't count.
Thirty minutes until touchdown.
Prepare for landing.
Wrap it up.
Cut the chatter. Let's go.
This is another version
of booby-trapping a resource.
- Right, I see.
- This one's designed to blind.
Smoke clings to the eyes.
That's an application
of the hummingbird trap.
You scare people
so they flee in this direction
into what they think
is a safe haven.
Two-tiered explosion.
You allow people enough time
to rush in, help the wounded, then...
- A second bomb.
- Right.
Second one goes off here.
I guess there are
no rules anymore about
what a person can do
to another person.
I don't think Snow used any
rulebook when he hijacked Peeta.
Welcome to District 2.
I'm Corporal Homes.
You follow me, please.
Don't worry.
It's just how the loyalists
say "Good morning."
President Coin,
we're indebted to you
for the reinforcements
and the Mockingjay.
But I'm not sure that
anyone outside of 2
knows what
we've been up against.
This is The Nut.
The Capitol's headquarters
for all offensive operations.
It's manned by both military
and civilian personnel
from District 2.
As you can see,
the fortress lies so far beneath
the bedrock, it's untouchable.
Yesterday, we attempted
to take the northeastern gate.
The enemy countered from higher up
and we were forced to pull back.
We took heavy losses.
Could we create a decoy?
Send troops towards one gate,
launch a staggered attack
on another.
Whose troops do you propose
as a decoy, commander?
We have the Mockingjay.
Don't underestimate her.
We could use her
to erode support.
She may be able to sway
some of the loyalists.
You've been underground
a long time, Madam Coin.
This isn't like
the rest of Panem.
Support for The Capitol
runs deep here.
Then there is
no sacrifice too great.
We need to control the arsenal
inside that fortress.
Even with every district
in this alliance,
we are outgunned.
I won't commit my people
to a ground assault
just to pillage weapons.
Commander Paylor,
your people have suffered
more than just about anyone else
at the hands of The Capitol.
Which is why I won't
condone a mass suicide.
If we don't take District 2,
we won't get into The Capitol.
Would it be enough to disable
the fortress... instead of taking it?
What do you
have in mind?
You think of it
like a wolf den.
You're not gonna fight your way in,
so you've got two choices.
You trap the wolves inside,
or you flush 'em out.
If we can't attack
straight on,
then couldn't we use
our hovercraft
to strike around it?
We'll use the mountains.
We'll hit weak spots
in the peaks.
We could design the bomb targets
in sequence using seismic data.
Trigger avalanches.
Block all exits,
cut off their supplies.
You make it impossible for them
to launch their hovercraft.
Bury them alive.
We'd forfeit any chance
to control the weapons.
Yes, but we'd face
a weakened Capitol.
There's civilians in there.
They should be given
a chance to surrender.
Could use one of the supply
tunnels for the evacuees.
It's a luxury we weren't given
when they firebombed 12.
There's gotta be a better way.
I suggest we try the avalanche,
but leave the train tunnel alone.
Civilians can escape
into the square,
where our armies will be
waiting for their surrender.
We should have every
available medic standing by.
And if they won't surrender?
Then we will need a compelling
voice to persuade them.
Red flag, this is blue leader.
Form up on Charlie Tango,
1,500 meters out.
All bombers are outbound.
What's the difference, Katniss?
Crushing the enemy in a mine
or blowin' them outta the sky
with one of Beetee's arrows.
It's the same thing.
We were under attack
in District 8.
And that hovercraft
wasn't filled with civilians.
Doesn't matter.
Even if those civilians
are just moppin' floors,
they're helping the enemy.
And if they have to die,
I can live with that.
No one who supports
The Capitol is innocent.
With that kinda thinking,
you can kill whoever you want.
You can send kids off
to The Hunger Games
to keep the districts in line.
It's war, Katniss.
Sometimes killing
isn't personal.
Figured if anyone knew that,
it was you.
I, of all people, know
that it's always personal.
Don't worry, Katniss,
there'll be survivors.
Let's focus on
what it is you gotta say.
Now, Plutarch wrote
a speech for you...
I'm not saying that.
Okay. Didn't think so.
Let's, uh...
But just remember,
you're talking to everybody.
Not just the rebels,
but The Capitol,
the survivors in 2.
We want them
to lay down their arms.
So you might wanna experiment
with a little
sensitivity, warmth.
Make it quick,
you're exposed.
This is Katniss Everdeen,
speaking to all of the loyalists
from the heart of District 2.
Survivors! Inbound!
Ready! Ready! Guns up!
On the ready. Guns up!
We gotta get you back.
Here they come!
Weapons tight!
Everybody, stand by!
On the ground!
Put your weapons down.
Get on the ground!
Put your weapons down now!
Weapons down!
You! Put it down!
Put it...
- Put your weapons down!
- Drop it!
Drop your weapon!
You! Drop it.
Drop the gun!
Drop it!
- Hold your fire!
- Stop!
Stop!
- Hold your fire!
- Stop!
- He needs help!
Hold your fire!
Drop it!
Give me one reason
I shouldn't shoot you.
Drop the gun!
I can't.
I guess that's the problem,
isn't it?
We blew up your mine.
You burned
my district to the ground.
We each have every reason
to want to kill each other.
So if you wanna kill me, do it.
Make Snow happy.
I'm tired of killing
his slaves for him.
I'm not his slave.
I am.
That's Why I killed Cato.
And he killed Thresh.
And Thresh killed Clove.
It just goes
around and around.
And who wins?
Always Snow.
I am done being
a piece in his game.
District 12, District 2.
We have no fight.
Except the one The Capitol gave us.
Why are you fighting the rebels?
You're neighbors.
You're family.
These people
are not your enemy.
We all have one enemy.
And that's Snow.
He corrupts everyone
and everything.
He turns the best of us
against each other.
Stop killing for him.
Tonight, turn your weapons
to The Capitol.
Turn your weapons to Snow.
Tonight, turn your
weapons to The Capitol.
Turn your weapons to Snow.
Hold your fire.
A toast.
Antonius, with our best troops
crushed in the mountains
and the rebels
marching on us as we speak,
what did we celebrate?
The death of
the Mockingjay, sir.
If Peeta didn't kill her,
her own arrogance did.
Of course.
That's the same facile thinking
that led you to divert our best
Peacekeepers into District 2.
You have a habit of burying
people before they're dead.
If the Mockingjay were gone,
the rebels would already be
using her as a martyr.
No, Minister Antonius,
I'm afraid that is not
what we were toasting at all.
Sir, the rebels
can be held off out...
The rebels will reach
the outskirts of The Capitol
in a matter of days.
We'll evacuate the outer
blocks to let them in.
I want all anti-aircraft
defenses ready,
so we're secure
from the skies.
Lure them into the city,
and then our Gamemakers
will make them pay
for every inch with blood.
I want every camera watching.
We'll turn their advance into
a celebration of suffering.
Let each moment be captured
for all posterity.
So, what did we toast tonight,
Minister Antonius?
We toasted a glorious era...
...coming to its bitter end.
Well, there she is.
The Mockingjay.
Oh, that speech you gave.
Oh, man, feel.
I mean, I still have goose bumps.
You don't mind, do you?
They cut off my supply of morphling.
There's this head doctor that
comes in and sees me every day,
trying to help me adjust to reality.
Like some guy from this rabbit's warren
actually knows anything
about my reality.
At least 20 times in a session,
he tells me that I'm totally safe.
Safe from The Capitol.
Safe from Snow.
What about you, Mockingjay?
You feeling totally safe?
- Till I got shot.
- Oh, please.
The bullet didn't
even touch you.
Cinna saw to that. Of course,
your costume would be bulletproof.
So what are your injuries?
Bruised ribs, bruised lung.
I'm surprised they haven't
found you a new lung.
I mean, I've got two.
Do you want one of mine?
I mean, it's everybody's job
to keep you alive.
- Is that why you hate me?
- Partly.
You're also a little
hard to swallow.
The whole tacky romance drama
and the "defender
of the hopeless" act.
Even though it's not an act.
Which makes it
even more unbearable.
Feel free to take
any of this personally.
You should have
been the Mockingjay.
Nobody else would
tell you what to say.
But nobody likes me.
- They're afraid of you.
- Maybe here,
but... in The Capitol,
you're the only thing
that they're scared of.
It's just stuff
my family brought.
It's from Peeta.
Yeah.
They messed us up
pretty good, didn't they?
We showed him
footage of your speech in 2.
He had real memories of you.
That still doesn't mean
I'm going in there.
He's strapped down.
He can't hurt you.
No. This is different. Haymitch,
I really don't want to.
It doesn't matter what you want.
It's for Peeta.
What's the harm in trying?
I watched you die.
- You look terrible.
- You've looked better.
You're not even remotely nice
to say that to me now.
I was never the nice one.
You were.
When I saw you die,
I remembered something.
About the bread.
I remember... you in the rain.
And I burned it on purpose.
To give it to you.
I remember
my mother hitting me.
I was supposed
to give it to the pig.
That was the first
we'd eaten in days.
Why would I take
a beating like that for you?
Because you were kind
and generous.
- And people said you loved me.
- Did people say you love me?
They said that's why Snow
tortured you. To hurt me.
Snow says that everything that
comes out of your mouth is a lie.
All I know is that
I would have
saved myself
a lot of suffering,
if I'd just given
that bread to the pig.
I think the only thing left
to say is "thank you."
I need to be in The Capitol.
No, you have done your job.
You've been very successful
as the Mockingjay.
You've unified the districts.
And now we want you to rest.
And to heal.
The last the rebels saw me,
I was lying on the ground.
Katniss, we won't let this
momentum go to waste.
We'll shoot more propos
right here in 13,
showing them
that you're alive.
I should be with the troops.
It'll be like being
on the front lines.
As far as the soldiers know,
you survived
a bullet to the heart.
I think they'll understand
why you're not with them.
When we win this war,
we'll fly you in
for the surrender.
We'll need you
for the ceremony.
You're very valuable to us.
I'll do whatever
you need me to do.
From this day forth,
in sickness and in health,
for richer or poorer.
I promise to love
and cherish you each day.
I, Finnick Odair,
take you, Annie Cresta,
as my wife from this day forth.
Together or apart,
we will always be united.
One life, one purpose,
one destiny.
You may kiss the bride.
You saw Peeta, didn't you?
Did you tell him "Hi" for me?
We're old friends, you know.
We had adjoining cells
in The Capitol.
We're very familiar
with each other's screams.
I'm going to kill Snow.
Nothing good is safe
while he's alive.
And I can't make
another speech about it.
No more cameras.
No more propos.
No more Games.
He needs to see my eyes
when I kill him.
Now you're talking.
Find a way to The Capitol
when everybody's looking
the other way.
I hear the medics talking.
They're shipping supplies
for the front line
from hangar two
around midnight tonight.
Medicine, painkillers.
I was gonna go
steal some for myself,
but I guess I could just
stay here and cover for you.
Anybody can kill anybody,
Katniss. Even a president.
You just have to be willing
to sacrifice yourself.
Go on.
Don't you want Snow
to see you dance?
Hey, that's her.
That's Katniss Everdeen.
Hey. Thought you were
in the hospital.
I was.
Come on.
What is she doing?
I don't know, it's so frustrating
when she goes rogue.
This isn't just adolescent,
it's insubordination.
Put her on the first
hovercraft back.
Don't be ridiculous.
She can't come back now.
She's mythic.
At the front lines,
surviving a gunshot wound.
Couldn't have staged it
better myself.
Hmm. I know.
She's going to stay
where she is.
And whatever she's doing,
we conceived it.
It was our plan all along.
Of course it was.
Mr. Heavensbee,
you're the Gamemaker.
I want everyone to know,
whatever game she's playing,
she's playing for us.
I'm Commander Paylor
of District 8.
I'm a soldier, like all of you,
so here's what I know.
For the first time
in our lifetimes,
we're standing together
with 13 districts.
From what I see here,
we've already made history.
But history doesn't stop
to celebrate.
And we're facing an enemy
that will not change
and will never surrender.
President Snow has
pulled back Peacekeepers
to fortify the center
of the city.
He's evacuating residents
from the outer blocks.
These civilians will be
confused and desperate.
You are under orders
not to target them.
We're deploying medical brigades
to help anyone in need.
We'll show The Capitol people
who we are.
To slow our advance,
President Snow
is building
a minefield of traps
and lethal devices
called "pods."
The sadistic inventions
of Gamemakers
meant to make sport
of our deaths.
If our armies make it past
Peacekeepers and other defenses,
we'll converge in the center
of the city at Snow's mansion,
where we won't just
unlock his gates,
but unshackle all of Panem.
If we die, let it be for
a cause and not a spectacle.
If we succeed,
let it be for all of Panem,
and let it be forever.
Yes, you've already
made history.
But the future, our future,
starts tomorrow at dawn,
when we march together
into The Capitol.
Squad 451?
Looks like you got
your meals covered.
- Tryin' to be prepared.
- Don't lie to me.
We've been hunting together
all our lives.
I know when you're gonna
go off on your own.
You gonna leave me behind, too?
As your fellow soldier,
I suggest that
you stay with your unit.
But I couldn't stop you
if you wanted to come.
Hawthorne, Everdeen,
come meet your new unit.
I'm Lieutenant Jackson,
and I wanna introduce you
to your squad.
This is
Second Lieutenant Mitchell,
best sharpshooter in Panem.
These are the Leeg sisters.
First Combat Division.
And this is Corporal Homes.
Finnick?
- Are you with us?
- Looks like it.
That was a short honeymoon.
Yeah, well,
I guess we're gonna have to
have one in The Capitol.
- After we take it.
- Gather 'round.
Squad 451, you're my unit.
Lieutenant Jackson is
my second-in-command.
Each one of you is elite
in some form of combat.
But we are a non-combat unit.
So we'll be following days
behind the front-line troops.
You're to be the onscreen
faces of the invasion.
"The Star Squad."
It's been decided that
you're most effective
- when seen by the masses.
- So we're not gonna fight?
You'll do whatever
you're ordered to do, soldier.
It's not your job
to ask questions.
Yes, sir.
Our instructions are
to shoot propaganda footage
on the battle-scarred streets
of The Capitol.
You were handpicked
to intimidate their forces.
And inspire surrenders.
Even though we'll be
working on abandoned streets
miles behind the front lines,
I guarantee you,
wherever they put us,
it will not be safe.
This is a war zone.
It is likely that we'll
encounter both active pods
and Peacekeepers.
You're considered high-value
targets to The Capitol.
In the event of capture,
you'll be given
a nightlock pill.
A poison that
acts immediately.
Lieutenant Jackson,
do the honors.
I've already
briefed you on the pods.
I remind you,
they are on every block.
Our unit has
been given a Holo.
A database that contains
a detailed map of The Capitol
and a list of every known pod.
These pods can trigger
anything from bombs
to traps to mutts.
We cannot move
without this device.
There's no guarantee
that our database is complete.
There could be new pods
that we're not aware of.
Because we don't want
the Gamemakers to know
we have this intel,
it has a self-destruct on it.
You flip this switch,
say "nightlock" three times,
and it blows itself and anything
within a 10-foot radius.
Stay within our unit.
Even with the Holo,
it is likely that new pods
have been set.
Whatever they contain,
they are meant to kill you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to
the 76th Hunger Games.
I've never
seen this place so empty.
Just keep your eyes open.
Got a pod.
Let's take cover.
Shoot through
those two buildings.
Pollux... right here.
Castor.
Good.
When you're ready, Katniss.
Hold it. Pollux, tighter.
Okay.
All clear.
I don't think we can
get across this minefield.
Not without that Holo.
We're not gonna get it
off him while he's awake.
Let's make sure we're on
the same watch tonight.
Is that Peacekeepers?
451 to base.
We've got a truck coming in
from the south. Over.
Copy that. Over.
Stand down, everyone.
It's friendly.
My name is Peeta Mellark.
My home is District 12.
- Okay, stop.
- My name is Peeta Mellark.
- Hold up. Everyone relax.
- My home is District 12.
What are we doin'?
Jackson, cuff him.
Soldier, this is
just a precaution
till we can get everything
straightened out. Yeah?
My name's Peeta Mellark.
From District 12.
They want us
to add him to the propo.
Show that he's
on our side now.
We'll move forward
a few blocks tomorrow
and shoot the new footage.
He's not in control
of himself.
I say we schedule an
around-the-clock watch on him.
The Leegs till 1700,
Homes and Mitchell till 1900.
Give me a watch.
And if it really
came down to it,
you think
you could shoot him?
I wouldn't be shooting Peeta.
I'd be killing a Capitol mutt.
I'm not sure
that kind of a comment
recommends you for the job,
either, soldier.
Put her in the rotation.
He's gonna try to kill me.
Especially with
all this going on.
It's gonna set him off.
We'll keep him contained.
Why would Coin do this?
Here's all I know.
It was Peeta that she wanted
rescued from the arena.
She never liked you.
She doesn't like anybody
or anything she can't control.
So she would
put my life in danger?
She'd deny it, but...
What?
One way or another, this war
is gonna come to an end.
They promised a free election.
Maybe she's startin' to
see you as a threat.
Nobody would think
I'd be a leader.
But you'd throw
your support to someone.
Would it be her?
And if your immediate answer
isn't "yes,"
then you're dangerous.
She doesn't need you
as a rallying cry anymore.
These propos
can be done without you.
There's only one thing
you could do now
to add more fire
to this rebellion.
Die.
That's not gonna happen
under my watch, Katniss.
I'm plannin' for you
to have a long life.
Why?
You don't owe me anything.
Because you've earned it.
We've been here
before, you know.
What?
That look.
I've seen that look.
You're trying to decide
whether or not
you should kill me.
I never wanted to kill you.
And that's not
what I'm doing.
I saw it with my own eyes.
In the first Games.
In the first Games,
I thought you were
trying to help
the Careers kill me.
After that,
I always saw you... as an ally.
Friend, lover...
...Victor...
...fiancé,
...enemy, target, mutt.
And now ally?
Yeah, I'll add that
to the list of words
I use to try
to figure you out.
I'm sorry.
I just can't tell what's real
and what's made up anymore.
Then ask.
It's what Annie does.
Ask who?
Us. We're your unit now.
Your favorite color is green.
Is that real?
Yeah. That's real.
Yours is orange.
Not bright orange.
Soft, like the sunset.
Thank you.
You're a painter.
You're a baker.
You always sleep
with the windows open.
You never take sugar
in your tea.
You always
double-knot your shoelaces.
You were right.
I can't do this.
Guess we're not
leavin' anymore.
We're not going anywhere
without that Holo.
Listen up.
Mag's empty.
It's only for the propo.
Let's move. We're headed
five blocks north.
"To the citizens
of The Capitol,
our war is not with you."
To the citizens
of The Capitol,
our war is not with you.
"You will be a vital part
of the democracy
that follows our victory."
Be a vital part
of the democracy
that follows our victory.
- You got it.
- Okay.
Boggs. This is a good spot.
Through there,
in the courtyard.
Okay, let us clear it.
Got a pod.
Split. Take cover.
Stay back.
All clear.
Gale, Homes, with me.
Leegs, take the wings.
Everdeen, no!
Boggs!
- Hold your position!
- Boggs!
Grab the tourniquets
from the bag.
Squeeze his legs
as hard as you can.
It's okay.
The Holo. The Holo.
Unfit for command.
Transfer primary
security clearance...
Say your name.
Katniss Everdeen.
What did you just do?
Katniss, don't trust them.
Kill Peeta, if you have to.
- Do what you came to do.
- Boggs? Boggs?
- Come on. Come on.
- He's gone. He's gone.
Go, go, go!
- This way!
- Keep moving.
Let's go, soldiers!
- Get to higher ground!
- Move!
Finnick!
- Peeta!
- Mitchell!
Come on, come on!
Settle!
Come on!
Don't stop! Let's go!
Come on, come on!
We gotta move!
Get inside!
Everybody, inside!
Go! Upstairs! Go! Hurry up!
Move!
- Go! Go!
- Move!
Keep moving!
Keep moving to the top!
Go!
Hey, hey! I got you.
It's slowing down.
Gamemakers are still
putting on quite a show.
- 451 to base. Over.
- Hey, we better move.
If Peacekeepers didn't know
where we were, they do now.
Those surveillance
cameras caught us.
451 to base.
Come in.
This is a bad spot.
We need to move now.
451 to base. Over.
I can't get a signal.
But I can get us back to base.
Everdeen, give me the Holo.
Everdeen, what did I just say?
The Holo. Come on, let's go.
Boggs gave it to me.
What are you talking about?
He did. He transferred
security clearance to her.
I saw him.
And why would he do that?
I'm on special orders from Coin.
To do what?
To assassinate
President Snow.
I don't believe that
for one second.
As your new unit commander,
I order you to transfer security
clearance to me now.
I can't do that.
Let's not
lose our heads here.
I'm not asking you again,
Everdeen.
Give me that Holo.
She's telling the truth.
Plutarch wants it televised.
He thinks if we could film
the Mockingjay
assassinating Snow,
it'll make
The Capitol surrender
before the casualties
get too high.
While we're arguing,
there's 100 Peacekeepers
on their way here.
Boggs promised me that
when the time came,
you would help me.
All right, soldier,
Holo's yours.
I don't think we're gonna
leave any footprints.
We should move now.
And those cameras outside
should be
covered up by the oil.
She can't move
forward like this.
Her leg is too bad.
We have to evacuate her.
I'm sorry.
I'll stay with her.
As soon as
we make contact,
we will send somebody back.
I promise you.
All right, everybody,
move out. Let's go!
Let's get him up.
Can you walk?
Come on, this way.
Get these
curtains closed.
It's the Leegs.
Good afternoon.
I'm Caesar Flickerman.
Here with our
continuing coverage
of the defense of The Capitol.
Today, as our Peacekeepers
valiantly hold off the rebels,
our story takes
a surprising twist.
Katniss Everdeen,
our once favorite daughter,
has infiltrated the city
with some of the victors,
whose names
are all too familiar.
Finnick Odair
and Peeta Mellark.
Hmm.
Clearly, some alliances
don't last forever.
Take a look at what happened
just a moment ago,
when our Peacekeepers cornered
Katniss Everdeen
and her band
of foolish rebels.
Whatever arrogance
brought this treacherous girl
back to us,
you are about to witness
a great victory,
not only for The Capitol,
but for Panem.
So there you have it.
Katniss Everdeen,
the Girl on Fire,
a girl who inspired
so much violence,
seems to have met
a violent end herself.
Stay tuned for more information.
Caesar Flickerman. Thank you.
So now that we're dead,
what are we gonna do?
Isn't it obvious?
The next move
is to kill me.
I murdered
one of our squad members.
Katniss is right.
I'm a mutt.
And it's only a matter of time
before I snap again.
I'm not in control.
I need a nightlock pill,
so I can die when I need to.
If it gets to that point,
I'll kill you myself.
I don't think
I ever really understood
The Capitol until now.
You eat like this,
you'll believe anything.
So Katniss Everdeen,
a poor unstable girl
with nothing
but a small talent
with a bow and arrow, is dead.
Not a thinker, not a leader.
Simply a face
plucked from the masses.
Was she valuable?
She was extremely valuable
to your rebellion
because you have no vision,
no true leader among you.
You call yourselves
an alliance.
But we saw what that means.
Your soldiers are
at each other's throats.
Good evening. For those of you
who don't know me,
please, allow me
to introduce myself.
I am President Alma Coin,
leader of the rebellion.
I have interrupted a broadcast
from your President
in which he attempted to
defame a brave young woman.
"A face picked from
the masses," he called her.
Plucked.
As if a leader, a true leader,
could be anything else.
I had the privilege of knowing
a small-town girl
from the Seam in District 12
who survived the Hunger Games
and the Quarter Quell
and rose up and turned
a nation of slaves
into an army!
Dead or alive,
Katniss Everdeen
will remain the face
of this revolution.
She will not have
died for nothing.
I had no idea
I meant so much to her.
Her vision and ours
will be realized.
A free Panem
with self-determination for all.
And in her memory,
we will all find the strength
to rid Panem
of its oppressors.
Thank you. And be safe.
Snow's in his mansion.
Where is that?
That's us.
That's the City Circle.
It's at least
70, 75 blocks north.
- Seventy-five blocks?
- Uh-huh.
Nobody knows we're alive.
This is our chance.
These buildings. Do these
look over Snow's gardens?
- I...
- They do.
If he goes outside at all,
I could get a clear shot.
We're getting
ahead of ourselves here.
Whether they're looking for us
or not, we are pinned down.
Hit that button.
Scan for pods.
Just about every ten steps.
Yeah, that doesn't even
show the new ones.
So we can't go anywhere
in the streets.
And the rooftops
are just as bad.
There might be another way.
My brother knows
these tunnels really well.
He worked sanitation
down here.
Right after they
made him an Avox.
Hey. Hey.
You gonna be okay?
Look at me. Look at me.
We're gonna get through this.
I promise.
Took us five years to
buy his way outta here.
He didn't see the sun once.
We're too exposed here.
Sir, should I call
for your doctor?
- What did you say?
- Shall I call for your doctor?
I hope you've wakened me
for something more urgent
than an old man's health.
They survived.
I don't know how.
We picked them up
on a surveillance cam.
Let me see. I...
I need to see for myself.
It's her.
It is her.
The arena has
moved underground.
Looks clear.
Everybody okay?
Yeah.
All right, everybody,
we're gonna stop here for a bit
and get some rest, yeah?
I'll take first watch.
Hey, Peeta.
Just tuck in there.
All right,
settle in, everybody.
Katniss? Your watch.
You know, The Capitol,
they used tracker jacker
venom on me.
That's what
the doctors in 13 said.
You were stung once, too.
Real or not real?
Real.
When they used
the venom on me,
they would show me
pictures of my life.
But some weren't real.
They changed them.
At first, they all...
They all blurred together.
But now... Now I can
sort them out a little.
Like the ones that
they changed,
they have this quality...
It's like they're shiny.
They've been glossed over.
You should get some rest.
You're still trying
to protect me.
Real or not real?
Real.
That's what you and I do.
Keep each other alive.
Katniss. Katniss. Katniss.
Katniss?
What is that?
We gotta go.
We gotta get outta here now.
- Keep your voice down.
- Mutts! They released mutts.
Pollux, what's
the fastest way out?
Come on! Go! Go!
- Go! Go! Go! It's mutts!
- Come on, come on, come on!
Pollux,
lead us out of here!
Come on!
Castor!
Fall back!
Move!
Katniss, come on! Move!
Katniss!
Go, go, go, go, go!
Go, go, go!
Katniss!
- No!
- Finnick!
Finnick!
Katniss!
Nightlock. Nightlock. Nightlock.
Come on, come on,
come on, come on. Let's go.
Keep moving! Keep moving!
Ow!
Go! Go!
Keep going! Keep going!
Peeta, come on!
Peeta!
Peeta, we have to
keep going!
I'm a mutt!
I can't keep control!
- Yes, you can!
- Leave me! I'm a mutt!
Look at me! Look at me.
Stay with me.
Always.
Come on.
I know where we are!
I know a place.
Up those stairs.
Keep going.
Someone's coming.
Shut the door,
shut the door!
No, Katniss,
it's okay, it's okay.
It's okay.
Tigris, do you remember me?
I'm with Plutarch's
underground.
We need your help.
Clear!
I know you.
You were a stylist in the Games.
Until Snow decided I wasn't
pretty enough anymore.
I'm here to kill him.
Gale's gonna need stitches.
I made it up.
All of it.
There is no special mission
from Coin.
There's only my plan.
Everyone that's dead is dead
because of me. I lied.
We know. We all knew.
- The soldiers from 13?
- They did, too.
Do you really believe
that Jackson thought
you had orders from Coin?
She trusted Boggs and he clearly
wanted you to go on.
I never meant
for this to happen.
I failed. I...
I killed them.
I killed Finnick.
I'm sorry, Pollux.
I'm so sorry.
Glimmer,
Marvel, Mags...
...Clove, Wiress, Rue.
What do all those deaths mean?
They mean that our lives
were never ours.
There was no real life
because we didn't
have any choice.
Our lives belong to Snow
and our deaths do, too.
But if you kill him,
Katniss...
If you end all of this,
all those deaths,
they mean something.
Cinna, Boggs, Castor,
Jackson, Finnick.
They chose this.
They chose you.
You should keep these clean.
Otherwise they'll get infected.
You should cuff me.
It's not safe with me yet.
I have moments
when I'm here.
And my memories
are getting better, but...
...other times it's like
I'm sleepwalking.
You should cuff me.
Thanks.
No problem.
I can't sleep.
Yeah, I haven't slept
in days, either.
I should've volunteered to take
your place in the first Games.
No, you couldn't have.
No, she never
would have forgiven you.
She needed you to be there
and take care
of her family and you did.
She can't lose you.
She really loves you.
And the way she kissed you
in the Quarter Quell.
She never kissed me like that.
Oh, just part of the show.
No. No, you won her over.
You gave up
everything for her.
Well, it's not gonna be
an issue much longer.
I doubt all three of us
are gonna make it out of this.
And if we do, then...
...it's her problem
who to choose, right?
Yeah.
I do know
that Katniss will pick
whoever she can't
survive without.
Mortar shells. It's not ours.
Peacekeepers must be shellin'
the rebels outside the city.
That's not outside the city.
Sun's comin' up.
There's some small-arms fire.
Could be Paylor, maybe Lyme.
Rebels are close.
This is it.
To all Capitol citizens
more than a half mile
outside the City Circle,
I am announcing
a mandatory evacuation.
Come to the mansion.
I am promising you
shelter and sanctuary.
All refugees,
come to my home.
There you will be
provided with food,
medicine,
safety for your children,
and you will have
my solemn oath
to protect you
until my dying breath.
Wish he'd hurry up
with that last part.
Our enemy is not like us.
They do not share our values.
They have never
known our comfort
and our sophistication.
And they despise us for it.
Make no mistake.
They are not coming
to liberate us.
They are coming
to destroy our way of life.
They are coming to bury us.
Is he still in the mansion?
Peeta?
Yeah. I recognize the room.
Where is that?
About five blocks away.
We're right here.
Off the Avenues.
Mansion's here.
What about the pods?
They'll probably
deactivate the pods
around here
for the residents' safety.
That could work.
I could get close enough.
Every Peacekeeper's
gonna be waiting.
Next to our faces
on every billboard.
Snow's offering shelter
to all the refugees.
Head straight north.
There's gonna be
thousands of refugees.
Just get into that stream
and don't look up.
We got one shot.
Let's make it count.
Good luck, Katniss.
Thank you.
Pollux.
Tigris, thank you
for everything you've done.
Katniss, let me
come with you, okay?
I can be a good distraction.
They know my face.
- No, I'm not losing you again.
- You'll be safer with us.
What if Peacekeepers
are searching the houses?
And if he's captured...
Then give me a nightlock pill, okay?
I'm not goin' back.
Stay alive.
If I see you again,
it's gonna be a different world.
Ready, Katniss?
Let's go.
By order of President Snow,
all residents must proceed
to the Presidential Estate.
Please, continue to move forward
in a calm and orderly fashion.
Additional food,
medicine and clothing
will be provided upon arrival.
By order of President Snow,
all residents must proceed
to the Presidential Estate.
Please, continue to move forward
in a calm and orderly fashion.
Additional food,
medicine and clothing
will be provided upon arrival.
By order of President Snow,
all residents must proceed
to the Presidential Estate.
Please, continue to move forward
in a calm and orderly fashion.
Additional food,
medicine and clothing
will be provided upon arrival.
By order of President Snow,
all residents must proceed
to the Presidential Estate.
Please, continue to move forward
in a calm and orderly fashion.
Additional food,
medicine and clothing
will be provided upon arrival.
By order of President Snow...
Keep moving.
...all residents must proceed
to the Presidential Estate.
Please, continue to move forward
in a calm and orderly fashion.
Additional food,
medicine and clothing
will be provided upon arrival.
It's the rebels!
The rebels
are attacking!
- Rebels!
Run! Run!
Mama! Mama!
Come on!
Come on, come on!
Shoot me!
Stay calm.
Bring your children forward.
The gates will
open momentarily.
The children
will be received first.
Stay calm.
Bring your children forward.
The gates will
open momentarily.
The children
will be received first.
Mom!
Stay calm.
Bring your children forward.
The gates will
open momentarily.
The children
will be received first.
It's The Capitol!
Gifts from The Capitol!
Gifts!
Medic!
- Medic!
- Make a hole!
Medics coming in!
Bring a stretcher!
This way, this way!
Prim?
Primrose!
Prim!
Hey.
I need you to lie back.
You're okay.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Fight was over after The Capitol
dropped those bombs
to defend the palace.
The rebels walked right in.
Don't, Katniss.
The ointment's working.
Everybody felt it.
Peacekeepers, palace guards.
They had kids in there, too.
It was...
It was over after that.
Mom?
I remember the first
time I brought you here.
And here we are.
I brought all your things.
Well, I'll leave you
to get settled.
Sorry, ma'am.
Can't let you pass.
Let her in.
On my authority.
She has a right
to anything behind that door.
That's a nice one.
The colors are lovely,
of course.
But nothing says
perfection like white.
I was hoping
you'd find your way here.
There are so many things
we should discuss.
But I have a feeling
your visit will be brief,
so first things first.
I wanted to tell you
how very sorry I am
about your sister.
So wasteful. So unnecessary.
Anyone could see the game
was over by that point.
In fact, I was just about to
issue an official surrender
when they released
those parachutes.
You released those parachutes.
You really think
I gave the order?
We both know I'm not
above killing children.
But I'm not wasteful.
I take life
for specific reasons.
And there was no reason
for me to destroy
a pen full of
Capitol children.
None at all.
I must concede, it was
a masterful move on Cain's part.
The idea that I was bombing
our own helpless children
to hold back the rebels...
It turned the last of
my guards against me.
There was no resistance left
inside The Capitol
or the mansion.
Do you know it aired live?
There's a particular savvy
in that, isn't there?
I'm sure she wasn't
gunning for your sister, but...
...these things happen in war.
My failure was in being so
slow to grasp Coin's plan.
She let The Capitol and the Districts
destroy one another,
then she stepped in to
take power with 13's arsenal.
Oh, make no mistake,
she intends to
take my place now.
But I've been watching you.
And you watching me.
I'm afraid we've both
been played for fools.
I don't believe you.
Oh, my dear Miss Everdeen.
I thought we'd agreed
never to lie to each other.
President Coin asked for you.
You never came to see me.
I wanted to, but...
Was it ours?
The bomb.
The delayed explosion.
The trap.
To draw more people in.
Was that you?
I don't know.
All I know is...
...that I was supposed to
take care of your family.
Now I'm sorry I couldn't.
You can't protect
anyone in an arena.
Goodbye, Gale.
What's this?
The remaining Victors.
Won't you join us?
I have invited you all here
for several reasons,
but first,
I have an announcement.
I have taken the burden
and the honor
of declaring myself
Interim President of Panem.
Interim? Exactly how long
is that interim?
We have no way
of knowing for certain.
But it's clear that people
are far too emotional right now
to make a rational decision.
We'll plan an election
when the time is right.
But I have called you here
for a far more important vote.
A symbolic vote.
This afternoon,
we will execute Snow.
Hundreds of his accomplices
also await their deaths.
Capitol officials, Peacekeepers,
torturers, Gamemakers.
But the danger is,
once we begin,
the rebels will not stop
calling for retribution.
Thirst for blood is
a difficult urge to satisfy.
So I offer
an alternative plan.
Majority of four may approve it.
No one may abstain.
The proposal is this.
In lieu of these
barbaric executions,
we hold
a symbolic Hunger Games.
You wanna have
another Hunger Games
with The Capitol's children?
- You're joking?
- Not in the slightest.
Is this Plutarch's idea?
It was mine.
It balances the need
for revenge
with the least loss
of human life.
- You may cast your votes.
- No.
No, obviously not.
This is crazy.
I think it's more than fair.
Snow's got a granddaughter.
I say "yes."
So do I.
Let them have a taste of it.
You guys,
this way of thinking
is what started
these uprisings.
I vote "no." With Peeta.
So would Finnick,
if he were here.
Well, he's not.
- Because Snow killed him.
- No.
We need to stop viewing
each other as enemies.
It's down to Katniss
and Haymitch.
I get to kill Snow.
I expected no less of you.
Then I vote "yes."
For Prim.
Haymitch?
I'm with the Mockingjay.
That carries the vote.
Excellent.
We'll announce the Games tonight,
after the execution.
Well, it's bound to be
quite the show.
Oh, you look lovely as ever.
Just beautiful.
Finishing touches.
Welcome to the new Panem.
Today, on the
Avenue of the Tributes,
all of Panem, a free Panem,
will watch more than
a mere spectacle.
We are gathered to witness
an historic moment of justice.
Today, the greatest friend
to the revolution
will fire the shot
to end all wars.
May her arrow
signify the end of tyranny
and the beginning
of a new era.
Mockingjay,
May your aim be as true
as your heart is pure.
No!
Kill him!
Kill him! Kill him now!
I'll say this for you, Katniss.
You don't disappoint.
Well, Plutarch
gave me a letter for you.
I don't want it.
You never make it easy, do you?
Okay. I'll read it for you.
"Katniss, maybe the country was
shocked tonight by your arrow,
but once again, I was not.
You were exactly
who I believed you were.
I wish I could give you
a proper goodbye.
But with both Coin
and Snow dead,
the fate of the country
will be decided tonight,
and I can't be seen
at your side.
Tonight, the 12 District leaders
will call for a free election.
There's little doubt
that Paylor will carry it.
She's become
the voice of reason.
I'm sorry so much
burden fell on you.
I know you'll never escape it.
But if I had to
put you through it again
for this outcome, I would.
The war's over.
We'll enter that sweet period
where everyone agrees not to
repeat the recent horrors.
Of course, we're fickle, stupid
beings, with poor memories
and a great gift
for self-destruction.
Although, who knows?
Maybe this time, we'll learn.
I've secured you a ride
out of The Capitol.
It's better for you
to be out of sight.
And when the time is right,
Commander Paylor
will pardon you.
The country
will find its peace.
And I hope
you can find yours.
Plutarch."
What now?
Home.
We go home.
I couldn't let you go
without a proper goodbye.
It's your job to take care
of yourself now, Katniss.
Promise me you'll find it.
Find What?
The life of a Victor.
- Goodbye, Effie.
- Goodbye, my girl.
Effie, don't be a stranger.
- Take care of her.
- I will.
She's gone.
Get out!
Get out! Prim is gone!
Prim is gone!
She's dead!
And she's not coming back!
Get out! Get out!
Peeta?
Hey.
You came home.
Yeah.
I found these, uh,
out by the edge of the forest.
It's a primrose.
So sorry, Katniss.
"You'll be happy to hear
that Katniss' mother
has been training new medical
units in The Capitol.
Gale has been promoted
to a captain in District 2
to help keep order
and security.
And I am loving
every moment with my son
who reminds me every day
of his father.
We've all suffered so much.
But we owe it
to their memories
and to our children to do
our best with these lives.
I hope you're both
finding some peace.
Annie."
I solemnly swear
to the best of my ability,
to preserve, protect,
and uphold the rights
of every citizen of Panem.
There's Plutarch,
right in the middle of it all.
And they say
no one ever wins the Games.
You love me.
Real or not real?
Real.
Oh.
Did you
have a nightmare?
I have nightmares, too.
Someday I'll explain it to you.
Why they came,
why they won't ever go away.
But I'll tell you
how I survive it.
I make a list in my head
of all the good things
I've seen someone do.
Every little thing
I can remember.
It's like a game.
I do it over and over.
Gets a little tedious
after all these years, but...
...there are
much worse games to play.